JIVKO ATANASSOV

330 Fisher Ave, Piscataway, NJ 08854 cell: 908 472 0799 email: zhim57@yahoo.com

Professional Profile:

Creative problem solver with great multitasking ability and strong interpersonal and negotiation skills, proven team leader, strong motivator, consistently exceeding productivity goals.

Strong computer background in Excel spreadsheets, macros and pivot tables, Microsoft word, presentations in power point and specialized software: power stow, AS400, oracle terminal systems etc.

Proficient with Outlook and Mozilla thunderbird email systems

Fluent in English, Russian and Bulgarian, IFIA certified

EXPERIENCE

Marine Consultant - Oct 2018 - present - Amicus Shipping LLC, Piscataway, NJ

Providing various services to maritime industry including cargo surveys, bunker surveys.

Ship Agent: 15 June2014- 21 Sept 2018 Norton Lilly international , Elizabeth NJ

Supervisor: Desmond Michael- Port Manager

Tel: 908-353-8400, Cell: 973-417-6439

- -Managing vessel operations for Maersk Vessels for the ports of New York and New Jersey,
- Working with various vendors to assure vessels will dock and sail in the schedule windows and cargo operations carry on with no delays or obstructions
- arranging clearance and delivery of spares crew and bunkers to the vessel
- -Coordinating vessel arrivals and departures with appropriate parties (i.e.: terminal, tugs, lines, pilots, etc.) to facilitate smooth berthing and un-berthing and avoid any unnecessary expenses.
- -Communicating with vessel and terminal and troubleshooting any cargo stowage issues, damage problems, reefer problems etc.

Confer with terminal and pass to vessel ganging/labor ordered with stevedore and terminal operator to allow vessel time planning and operations planning.

- -Reviewing and processing port and vessel related invoices.
- -Updated all parties of vessel's progress, program and expected completion and sailing.
- -updated company and client web systems with the port call information.
- -Preparing and collecting document sets for customs and immigration clearance.
- -Providing 24/7 service
- -Proposing improvement of standard operations procedures, thus increasing efficiency and time/cost savings.
- -Created excel and email templates for document processing improvement

Inspector: 16 Mar 2014- 12 June 2014 Inspectorate Americas Corporation, Linden, NJ

Supervisor: Jim Carol Address: 1301 W Blancke St, Linden, NJ 07036

Phone: (908) 862-1717

- Assess quantity of petroleum cargo loaded or discharged by tankers; perform gauging; determine temperatures; calculate quantities of petroleum cargo on board vessels; inspect cofferdams & void spaces; check & seal valves to avoid cargo diversion; record incidents affecting cargo operations; assess & determine quantity of petroleum

cargo on vessels; calculate quantities of petroleum cargo with data on gauging, temperature, & gravity of cargo; compare quantities of petroleum delivered & received; perform marine surveys to determine quantities of cargo loaded or discharged.

IFIA certified

Inspector: 20 Oct 2012-15 Mar 2014 Amspec Services LLC, Linden, NJ

Supervisor: Denise Salotti , Address: 36 Mileed Way, Avenel, NJ 07001

Phone: (908) 862-7272

- Assess quantity of petroleum cargo loaded or discharged by tankers; perform gauging; determine temperatures; calculate quantities of petroleum cargo on board vessels; inspect cofferdams & void spaces; check & seal valves to avoid cargo diversion; record incidents affecting cargo operations; assess & determine quantity of petroleum cargo on vessels; calculate quantities of petroleum cargo with data on gauging, temperature, & gravity of cargo; compare quantities of petroleum delivered & received; perform marine surveys to determine quantities of cargo loaded or discharged.
- IFIA certified

Marine Superintendent: 01 Nov 2010- 17 Aug 2012 APL, Union, NJ

Supervisor, at that time: Brian Sewell, the new office address: APL (America) LLC

1 Meadowlands Plaza Suite 200,07074 EAST RUTHERFORD, NJ,

Phone +1 (201) 806 9550

- -determine the docking windows for APL vessels calling NYCT, prepare program and pass the information to fleet ,vessel and agents.
- -Calculate gangs/hours needed for the discharge and load and place labor orders with the terminal
- -coordinate with USCG any boarding and advise fleet to adjust scheduled arrivals.
- -Coordinate deliveries, repairs with the ship superintendents/managers and the terminal to reduce labor standby.
- Receive and load the arrival baplie files, prepare priority discharge plan and pass to the terminal
- -Analyze daily ops issues arising with vessels, inbound and outbound cargo or truckers find the root cause and advise proper departments for corrective actions.
- -Update vessel schedules in APL system.
- -Perform other tasks as required in the operations department.

Ship agent- 01 Jan 2007 20 Aug 2010 Norton Lilly International, Elizabeth, NJ

Supervisor: Desmond Michael- Port Manager 5080 Mclester Str, 3r floor, Elizabeth, NJ 07201 Tel: 908-353-8400, Cell: 973-417-6439

- -Managed the day to day terminal and vessel operations for the ports of New York and New Jersey,
- -Assured all husbandry activities of a vessels call in the port of NY/NJ are handled in the best possible way
- -Communicated with stevedores, port captains, contractors and terminal services provider and ensured no delays are incurred and all operations are executed accordingly as planned
- -Coordinated vessel arrivals and departures with appropriate parties (i.e.: terminal, tugs, lines, pilots, etc..) to facilitate smooth berthing and un-berthing and avoid any unnecessary expenses.
- -Communicated with vessel and terminal and troubleshot any cargo stowage issues, damage problems.

Confer with terminal and pass to vessel ganging/labor ordered with stevedore and terminal operator to allow vessel time planning and operations planning.

-Reviewed and processed port and vessel related invoices.

- -Updated all parties of vessel's progress, program and expected completion and sailing.
- -updated company and client web systems with the port call information.
- -Prepared and collected document sets for customs and immigration clearance.
- -Provided 24/7 service
- -Proposed improvement of standard operations procedures, thus increasing efficiency and time/cost savings.
- -Created excel templates for document processing automation
- -Made quick text templates to increase productivity of email.

Ship agent -May 2003-Jan 2007 Biehl & Co. LP NY, Iselin, NJ

Supeervisor Craig Smithline (at that time)

Address: 90 Woodbridge Center Dr #340, Woodbridge, NJ 07095

Phone: (732) 404-9813

Communicate with the different authorities, vendors and terminals to assure no time is lost during a vessels call. Prepare documents and keep all parties informed./ Prepare pro-forma disbursement account and send to principals.

EDUCATION

2020 Rutgers Full Stack Developer Bootcamp. Expected completion Nov 2020
1991-1998 Burgaski Svoboden Universitet , Burgas, (BFU Burgas free University) Bulgaria- M.A., Law.
1983-1989 Geo Milev High School, Burgas, Bulgaria- English
Sept 1989- March 1991 - Bulgarian Army - Artillery